cadence.com 2018-10-21

# Privacy Policy

#### Introduction

Your privacy is important to Cadence Design Systems, Inc. and its affiliates, each acting as a data controller (collectively, “Cadence”, “we”, “our”, and “us”). The following Privacy Policy discloses the information practices for Cadence, and Cadence websites, products or applications available for download through those websites that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “Sites”). Cadence may supplement or amend this policy by additional policies and guidelines from time to time. This Privacy Policy identifies the types of information gathered, how the information is used, and how the information is shared with others.

### Types of Information We Collect

##### Information You Provide to Us

We and our service providers collect any information that you provide to us, including, but not limited to, when you:

  * register for a seminar, webinar, or event;
  * create an account or a profile;
  * participate in our user community or otherwise contribute content to the Sites, such as by authoring a post on our forums or commenting on a blog post;
  * submit an employment application and/or resume, or fill out other employment documentation;
  * make a purchase;
  * provide feedback;
  * request information from us;
  * register for training courses;
  * download software;
  * sign up to receive electronic newsletters, blog posts, and other materials; or
  * contact us with a question, comment, feedback, or request, including service requests.

The information that you provide to us may include:

  * your name;
  * your place of employment and job title;
  * contact information such as physical address, email address, and phone number;
  * username, password, and other registration information;
  * demographic information, such as age, gender, preferences, and interests;
  * information you provide when submitting an employment application;
  * transaction-related information;
  * information you provide when you make a request or otherwise contact us; and
  * any other information you choose to make public on the Sites (e.g., information shared with other members of our user community).

##### Cookies & Analytics Information

As you navigate any of the Sites, we and our service providers may use cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to automatically collect certain information from your computer or mobile device over time and across different websites.

A cookie is a small text file that many websites save on your computer's hard drive when you visit a site. The Sites use both session cookies and persistent cookies to maintain your session state and to obtain information about your use of the Sites. Session cookies expire once you close your browser. Persistent cookies stay on your computer until you delete them. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Site.

The Sites also use web analytics services to analyse your Site use. The web analytics services, including Google Analytics, use cookies to evaluate your Site use by providing services about Site activity and internet usage to the website providers. For more information about Google Analytics, please visit: <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>. You can prevent Google’s collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB).

We and our service providers may automatically collect the following information about you:

  * IP address
  * Browser type and operating system
  * Webpages you view on the Sites
  * Clickstream data
  * Search terms you enter on the Sites
  * Domain name
  * E-mail address (to the extent that our servers automatically recognize it)
  * Information viewed and/or downloaded on the Sites.

This information helps us improve and customize the content or layout of the Sites.

##### Use of Information

We process personal data where the processing is necessary to perform the contract between you and Cadence, to take steps at your request prior to entering into such contract, or to comply with our legal obligations or exercise legal rights; or the processing is otherwise in Cadence’s legitimate interests in accordance with applicable law. In particular, we and service providers working on our behalf may use the information we collect for a number of purposes, as stated below.

The information we and our service providers may automatically collect may include your IP address, your browser type and operating system, the webpages you view on the Sites, clickstream data, the time and length of your visit to the Sites, the search terms you enter on the Sites, your domain name, your e-mail address (to the extent it is automatically recognized by our servers), and information viewed and/or downloaded on the Sites. This information helps us to improve the content of the Sites, and customize the content or layout of the Sites.

  * providing you with the information that you request;
  * managing your account and providing you with information about the Sites, such as changing your user profile, notifying you of recent updates to the Sites, and providing you with patch releases or warranty information;
  * processing any transactions or providing any services you have authorized, such as a purchase or service request, and maintaining and supporting our products to the extent necessary for the provision of the services;
  * delivering marketing communications, promotional materials, or advertisements as well as product news or notifications;
  * allowing us to improve the Sites and the products and services we provide, such as by better tailoring our content to our users’ needs and interests and improving site navigation;
  * generating and analyzing statistics about your use of the Sites, to the extent your data is properly pseudonymized; and
  * detecting, preventing, and responding to fraud, intellectual property infringement, violations of our Terms of Use, violations of law, or other misuse of the Sites, Cadence systems or assets.

We and service providers working on our behalf also may combine or aggregate any of the information we collect through the Sites or elsewhere for any of these purposes.

The provision of the information we collect is necessary to enter into an agreement with us. You are not obliged to provide the information. However, if you don’t, you might not be able to use some areas of the Sites and / or other services.

##### Disclosure of Information

We may share your information covered by this Privacy Policy with other individuals or other entities (such as direct mail organizations):

  * when we have your permission;
  * when you choose to make information public on the Sites, such as when you contribute a post to our Cadence Technology Forums;
  * to service providers who work on our behalf and have agreed to use the information solely to provide the services requested by Cadence, including, but not limited to, service providers that process payments, provide support services, or provide shipping services;
  * to service providers, advisors, and other third parties to the extent reasonably necessary to proceed with the negotiation or completion of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, provided that any third party that acquires our company will assume the rights and obligations regarding your information as described in this Privacy Policy; or
  * when we believe in good faith that such disclosure is to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to court orders or other legal process served on Cadence, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Cadence or users of the Sites; or (c) detect, prevent, or respond to fraud, intellectual property infringement, violations of our Terms of Use, violations of law, or other misuse of the Sites.

##### Security of Your Information

While we strive to maintain reasonable physical, technical, and administrative procedures to safeguard the information that we collect, we cannot ensure the absolute security of your information. We also are not responsible for the security of information you transmit to the Sites over networks that we do not control, including the Internet and wireless networks.

##### Children’s Privacy

The Sites are not directed to, nor do we knowingly collect information from, anyone under 13 years of age. If you become aware that your child has provided us with information without your consent, please contact us at the contact information listed below.  

##### Location of Your Information

Information covered by this Privacy Policy will be transferred to, stored at, and processed in the United States and other countries in which Cadence offices are located (as indicated on the [www.cadence.com](http://www.cadence.com/) website) or Cadence does business, which may not provide the same level of protection for your personal information as your home country. Before transferring your personal information, we will take steps to ensure that such data will be afforded the level of protection required under applicable data protection laws. For such data transfers, we may use the standard contractual clauses adopted by the European Commis

##### Retention Period

We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy. The criteria used to determine such retention periods include: (i) the length of time we have an ongoing relationship with you; (ii) whether there is a legal or business obligation to which we are subject; or (iii) whether a longer retention period is required or permitted by law, for example to maintain certain contractual or tax records.

##### Your Choices and Rights

You have the right to request access to and rectification or erasure of or restriction of processing or to object to processing of personal information, or request portability of personal information that Cadence holds about you. Please send any such requests to  [privacy@cadence.com](mailto:privacy@cadence.com). We will respond to your request as soon as reasonably practicable and in accordance with applicable law. To the extent required under legal obligations or local laws, some of your information may remain within our systems and other records.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a competent supervisory authority.

In some cases, we provide a means to create an account or a profile of information on the Sites. In such cases, you may access and correct certain information by accessing your account or profile. For example, to change your contact information on [www.cadence.com](http://www.cadence.com/), log in to your account and select the "My Account" link found on the top of the webpage.

If we have obtained your e-mail address in connection with your purchase of our goods or services, we may send you promotional or marketing e-mails in relation to similar goods or services. You may opt-out from receiving these e-mails by notifying us at the address specified at the bottom of any unwanted e-mail. These opt-out procedures may not be available for transactional or relationship messages, such as e-mails that are necessary to provide you with confirmation of a completed transaction (such as a purchase, service request, or change in your user profile), to provide you with warranty information regarding a particular product you purchased, to provide notification of changes of terms of service, or to provide you with important information about the use of a product that you have purchased or software that you have downloaded.

We may send you periodic mailings or telephone you to inform you of new products, services, or events.

You may set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. You may also set your browser to turn off cookies. If you do so, however, some areas of the Sites may not function properly. For more information about cookies and how to manage them, visit  [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

You may opt-out of our collection of analytics information through Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using Google’s [Ads Preference Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb) or at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. The Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on can be accessed [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). For further details on the use of Google Analytics, please see above chapters “Information Collected Automatically” and “Google Analytics”.

##### Links to Other Sites

The Sites may contain links to third-party websites and applications. Our provision of a link to any other website or application is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such other website or application or its contents. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for these third-party websites and applications or their content. Please be aware that the terms of our Privacy Policy do not apply to these third-party websites and applications.

##### Contact Information

Cadence welcomes your comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions, please contact Cadence Design Systems, the data controller, at  [privacy@cadence.com](mailto:%20privacy@cadence.com).

For your information, Cadence’s locations and contact information are available at  www.cadence.com/contact_us/Pages/default.aspx.

##### Privacy Policy Updates

If we change this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting a new Privacy Policy on this page and updating the “Last Revised” date below.

_Effective: September 2005  
Last Revised: June 2018_
